Okay, so in this video then, we are going
to cover these agile
estimation techniques.
Now, in a previous video, we covered the
predictive estimating methods.
In predictive, the estimating methods are
analogous, parametric, three point,
and bottom up.
So don't confuse the predictive estimation
methods with the agile
estimating techniques.
in a predictive environment, we are coming
up with an actual duration, right,
in terms of days, weeks, months,
hours, right?
We're coming up with an actual duration.
In the agile world, we're coming up with
what's known as a relative estimate.
In the agile world, you don't always come
up with, you know, days, weeks,
hours, at least not initially.
So during release planning, right, during
release planning, you never come up.
You don't have an actual date.
or timeline as such, it's all relative
estimate.
And even within a
sprint, initially, it won't
be necessarily in terms of hours or days.
It's going to be a relative estimate.
And what do we mean by relative?
Well, the size of relative to one another.
If we look at one particular user story,
and we think this is a small user story.
Now we're looking at
another user story, so we're
comparing this user
story to this user story.
If we consider this a small, you know,
the relative effort is small.
And this is about the
same relative effort, then
this would be considered
a small user story.
But then another user story could be
double the amount of effort.
Another user story could be triple the
amount of effort.
So first, we need to establish a
benchmark.
So the team, and this is something that
the team is going to be performing.
This is a responsibility of their team.
So based on this one benchmark,
now, they're going to be comparing these
user stories to determine
is this a higher level of
effort or a lower level of
effort and so on and so forth.
So these are some of the common estimation
techniques.
When it comes to agile, nothing real high
tech about agile.
The whole idea of agile
is low tech, high touch type
of thing, something that
anybody can understand.
So for example, then, one of the
estimation techniques is something called
t-shirt sizing and is literally as it
sounds.
T-shirt sizing.
What are the sizes of t-shirts?
I mean, literally, T-shirt
that you wear, you go to
a store and you fall into
one of these sizes, right?
Is it a small, medium, large, extra large,
extra-large, or an extra small?
So they use that same principle with user
stories.
Right?
Is this a small user story, a medium-sized
user story, an extra small, an extra
large, and so on and so forth,
right?
So nothing high-tech about that.
Then another method that PMI talks about
is something called story pointing,
and this uses a Fibonacci sequence.
Now, you don't need to understand how you
actually perform this
any amount of detail.
But a Fibonacci sequence, you know,
if you're not aware, it's just basically
you know, subsequent
numbers, right, the next number in
the sequence are the basically
two numbers added together.
So you start off with one, right,
and then two, then one plus two,
is 3, so the next number is 3.
Then 2 plus 3 is 5, so the next number in
sequence is 5.
Then 3 plus 5 is 8, so the next number in
the sequence is 8, and so and so forth.
5 plus 8 is 13, so it goes to 13.
So that's what the Fibonacci sequence is.
And story pointing essentially uses a
Fibonacci sequence.
And again, you don't necessarily need to
understand how you actually use a story
pointing, how you use a
Fibonacci sequence, you
just need to know
that that is a tool, right?
That is a tool and technique.
That is an estimation technique.
So whenever we talk about techniques,
right, if you hear the term in the exam,
right, which tool and technique is being
used and any of these techniques that we
are covering, that would be a tool and
technique.
So another one then is that uses a
modified, a type of modified Fibonacci
sequence, is something called planning
poker, right?
Now, you know, it sounds like a game and
it almost is a game.
Basically, you have the team members have
a deck of cards and these deck of cards
has a Fibonacci sequence on there or maybe
some kind of modified Fibonacci sequence.
Each card has one of those numbers,
right?
One, two, three, five,
eight, 13 and so and
so forth going up in a Fibonacci sequence.
And then based on that, team members are
going to determine the relative effort,
right, of each particularly user story.
This user story, I would give it a five.
This user story, I would give it a three
because it's a lower level of effort.
This one is a 13 because it's much bigger
and so and so forth.
Again, you're not going to be asked in any
detail necessarily.
You don't need to know in detail how to
perform it.
It just need to know that, yes,
this is a tool.
You come across the
term planning poker, then
you know this is an estimation technique.
And then you have coffee cup sizing,
right?
very similar, right, along the same lines
as t-shirt sizing, but in this case,
coffee cups, right?
So, and it is literally as it sounds,
right?
Small, medium, large, grande, venti.
Now, again, there's nothing rocket science
about this, right?
Nothing high tech about this.
Every team or every
organization, different industries,
they may use their own
estimation techniques as well.
But these are just, you
know, some of the more
common ones that you,
need to know for the exam.
Again, remember, though, don't confuse
these terms, right, with the
prioritization techniques or reaching a
consensus, right?
So, you know, the terms can sound very
similar.
This one is specifically agile estimation.
These are agile estimation techniques.
There's a separate video covering reaching
a consensus, the different consensus
techniques, separate video talking about
the different prioritization techniques.
And all of those terms,
the way they ask the
questions, it can get a
little confusing on the exam.
So make sure you can distinguish between
these terms.